Zhengvuan Yang

CONTACT Department of Computer Science, University of Rochester

585-435-3638

INFORMATION Rochester, NY 14627

zyang39@cs.rochester.edu

Website: http://cs.rochester.edu/u/zyang39/

RESEARCH INTERESTS My current major research interest is language-based visual content search and localization. My previous works mainly fall into the categories of vision+language and human-centered visual understanding, such as visual grounding by language in images and videos, human action recognition and parsing. Previous studies also include general video analyses such as emotion recognition, camera-based self-driving vehicles, etc.

EDUCATION

University of Rochester, Rochester, NY

Ph.D., Computer Science, Expected: Summer 2021

GPA: 3.94/4.0

• Advisors: Prof. Jiebo Luo

University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China

B.E., School of Electronic Engineering and Information Science (1206), June 2016

GPA: 3.93/4.3 (ranked 9/290)

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant Aug 2016 to present

University of Rochester, Rochester, NY

Advisor: Prof. Jiebo Luo

Research Intern Jan 2019 to Apr 2019

Tencent AI Lab in Bellevue, WA

Supervisor: **Dr. Boqing Gong, Dr. Liwei Wang** Visual Grounding with Natural Language Quires

Research Intern May 2018 to Aug 2018

SnapChat Research in Venice, CA

Supervisor: Dr. Yuncheng Li, Dr. Linjie Yang and Dr. Ning Zhang

Weakly-supervised Human Part Parsing

Research Intern May 2017 to Aug 2017

SAIC USA in San Jose, CA Supervisor: **Dr. Jerry Yu**

E2E Self Driving. Best Industry Related Paper Award (BIRPA) in ICPR 2018.

PUBLICATIONS

1. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Boqing Gong, Liwei Wang, Wenbing Huang, Dong Yu, Jiebo Luo, "A Fast and Accurate One-Stage Approach to Visual Grounding," *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019. (oral presentation).

2. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Tushar Kumar, Jiebo Luo, "Revisiting Tracking by Language," *in review*.

3. Mengshi Qi, Weijian Li, **Zhengyuan Yang**, Yunhong Wang, Jiebo Luo, "Attentive Relational Networks for Mapping Images to Scene Graphs," *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2019.









- 4. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Yuncheng Li, Linjie Yang, Ning Zhang, Jiebo Luo, "Weakly Supervised Body Part Parsing with Pose based Part Priors," *in review*.
- 5. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Yixuan Zhang, Jiebo Luo, 'Human-Centered Emotion Recognition in Animated GIFs with Facial Landmarks,' *IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME)*, 2019.
- 6. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Yuncheng Li, Jianchao Yang, Jiebo Luo, 'Action Recognition with Spatio-Temporal Visual Attention on Skeleton Image Sequences,' *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT)*, 2018.
- Zhengyuan Yang, Yixuan Zhang, Jerry Yu, Junjie Cai, Jiebo Luo, 'End-to-end Multi-Modal Multi-Task Vehicle Control for Self-Driving Cars with Visual Perceptions,'
 International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR), 2018. (oral presentation) Best Industry Related Paper Award (BIRPA)
- 8. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Yuncheng Li, Jianchao Yang, Jiebo Luo, 'Action Recognition with Visual Attention on Skeleton Images,' *International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)*, August 2018. (oral presentation)
- 9. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Amanda Kay, Yuncheng Li, Wendi Cross, Jiebo Luo, "Pose-based Body Language Recognition for Emotion and Psychiatric Symptom Interpretation," *in review*.
- 10. **Zhengyuan Yang**, Wendi Cross, Jiebo Luo, 'Personalized pose estimation for body language understanding,' *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)*, 2017. (oral presentation)

| Awards | Best Industry Related Paper Award (BIRPA) in ICPR 2018, (1/1258) | 2018 |
|--------|--|------|
| | National Scholarship, Top 3% | 2014 |
| | Huayu Scholarship, Top 3% | 2015 |
| | Elite Class of Information Science Scholarship | 2015 |

SERVICE Reviewer: IEEE TCSVT, Pattern Recognition, IEEE Access, CVPR 2020, ICIP 2018, 2019, ICME 2018

REFERENCES **Prof. Jiebo Luo**, Professor, University of Rochester, jluo@cs.rochester.edu

Dr. Boqing Gong, Research Scientist, Google, BoqingGo@outlook.com

Dr. Yuncheng Li, Research Scientist, Google, raingomm@gmail.com

Dr. Jerry Yu, Deputy Director, SAIC USA, jyu@saicusa.com